MUHAMMAD MUZAMMIL PEER

Mobile:+92-345-2196750

Email: <u>muzammilpeer987@gmail.com</u>

Web: https://qa.linkedin.com/in/muzammilpeer
Github: https://github.com/muzammilpeer

Location: Doha, Qatar

Profile

I am an open source enthusiast and self-motivated individual with sound experienced in mobile and web development. It's been wonderful 5+ years in software industry in which I have served several software companies in various roles, domains and technologies. I am an active player, initiator, contributor and capable to deliver software project from inception to deployment.

Skills

Mobile application development: (objective-c, swift, java, java script, angularjs, and jquery; developed native and hybrid apps in iOS and android)

Web services: (.net(c#), php, and java)

Web application development: (in **Java** [struts, oracle adf, blazeds with adobe flex, kendoUl, knockout with jersey webservices), **php**, **asp.net** and **c++ cgi**

Desktop development: objective-c(mac), c#(wpf and non wpf), c++(windows)

Platform used: MacOSX, Linux and Windows

Source Control & Bug tracking: SVN,Git, ibm-clearcase, jira,test director and hp-quality center

Database: Oracle, mySQL, SqlLite, MS-SQL and MongoDB

Experience

Sr. Mobile Consultant, Kahramaa; Doha,Qatar — **July,2016-Present**Working on mobile application majorly focus on iOS (Native, swift) and also involved in Gathering Requirements, Documentation, Source controlling (SVN), Application design and also giving my support to Web Service team to expose interconnected data for corresponding response.

Sr. Software Engineer, Systems Ltd ; Karachi, Pakistan — November, 2012-Present

Involved in multiple projects and support majorly in mobile development in native and hybrid solution targeting (iOS, android and windows phone), majorly involved in coding, application architecture, optimization and utilization out of the best solution to catch the superfine experience between end user, moreover being a member of enterprise web application department I also played my role in web application

development using java, adobe flex, html 5 and developed web services for end users in java and .Net.

Software Engineer, Nex Science LLC; Karachi, Pakistan — March, 2012-August, 2012

Working on mobile application majorly focus on iOS (iPhone and iPad) and also involved in gathering requirements and team management tasks on daily basis.

Software Engineer, HuLeTS — August,2011-February,2012
Working on mobile application majorly focus on iOS native (using cocatouch and cocos2d) also involved in gathering requirements, and proposing ideas and work independently on products. worked on web services development and database for complete solutions.

Education

NUCES-FAST, Karachi, Pakistan — BS-CS, 2011

Recommendations

Please visit my LinkedIn profile to view recommendation.

LinkedIn Profile URL: https://qa.linkedin.com/in/muzammilpeer